# Lucas (Luke) Wald

Former Senior Manufacturing Technology Engineer transitioned into a Software Engineer role after completing the Full Stack Web Development Certificate at the University of Minnesota. Over 9 years of experience in critical thinking, data analysis, communication, leadership, creativity, and customer service.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Full Stack Web Development Certificate** University of Minnesota

Sept 2023 - Dec 2023

- Hands-On learning in a fast paced academic environment.
- Emphasis on Full Stack Web Development
- Collaborated effectively in team settings, contributing to project planning, problem solving, and coding.
- As project manager for a group project, I successfully maintained clear communication and coordinated team efforts to deliver a successful web application in a short time frame

## **Bachelor of Arts, Biology**

2010 - 2014

St. John's University, Collegeville MN

Honors: Presidential Scholarship - Eldon Siehl Scholarship Study Abroad: Amazon Rainforest and Galapagos Islands, July 2012

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Sr Manufacturing Technology Engineer 3M, Maplewood MN

Aug 2015 - June 2023

Other Titles: Analytical Chemist 2015-17 | Advanced Chemist 2017-20

- Self taught myself FTIR analysis, became a company expert in that field.
- Awards: 3P Exceptional Award 2017, 3P Fundamental Award 2018, Quality Achievement Award 2018
- Solved problems that could have affected over \$1 billion in SVOP.
- Applied multiple analytical techniques to troubleshoot raw material, film, and adhesive issues that helped drive product and process improvements for a wide variety of 3M products and global plant locations.
- Job required balancing multiple objectives and projects, analyzing data, documenting, tracking, and communicating strategies to multi-functional business, technical, and manufacturing teams
- Resolved problems related to: research & development, product development, competitive analysis, process improvement, raw material second source qualifications, and customer complaints
- Discovered a raw material issue that had gone unsolved for years. Developed and implemented a quality control test at the supplier location.
- Interviewed and mentored summer interns who would later be hired.

## **Analytical Chemist** Volt Workforce Solutions - Contracted 3M, Maplewood MN

June 2014 - Aug 2015

- Method development for chemical analysis and material characterization of 3M products
- Quality control analysis through liquid and headspace gas chromatography

#### CONTACT

- St. Paul, MN (Open to Remote)
- Phone: +1-651-357-0781
- Email: <u>lukewald@hotmail.com</u>
- Linkedin: <u>/lucas-wald</u>
- GitHub: /wald14

#### **TECH STACK**

- React / Vite
- MongoDB / Mongoose
- MySQL / Sequelize
- JavaScript / JQuery
- CSS / Bootstrap / Chakra-Ui
- HTML
- Node
- Express
- GitHub
- REST API
- Handlebars

### **PROIECTS**

Portfolio: luke-wald-portfolio.netlify.app

- Sports Team Stat Web App (Passion / Individual Project)
- Role: Full Stack Web Developer
- MERN Web Application
- o github.com/Wald14/rubber-puck ies-web-app
- **Giftify** (Group Project)
- o Role: Full Stack Web Developer
- React / MongoDB
- o github.com/GrantMitchell24/ gift-guide
- Armory (Group Project)
- o Role: Project manager & Full Stack Web Developer
- JavaScript / MySQL
- github.com/mollvdotwhat/ mvc-armory
- Cocktail Generator (Group Project)
- o Role: Front End Developer
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- o github.com/MattoStark/ cocktail generator